Hello friends, how are you all?  I hope it will be
quite good.  So friends,
in today's video we will review an
IPO which has already opened.
ICICI
Prudential AMC LED's IPO will remain open between 12th to 16th December.  And this IPO
is in the news more because there
is a shareholder quota in it and
many people are already prepared for the shareholder quota
and the
advantage of the shareholder quota is that you can
apply twice.  Once
under the particular shareholder quota and the
second time you can
apply under the retail category or
under the HAI category, it is your
choice.  So if you get a chance twice, the
chances increase a little.
That's why there is more attraction.  Now there is attraction
but whether this company is good or not, whether it will be
profitable or not,
all these things are known in this video.
So first of all in this video we will
learn about GMP and anchor.  You will have some
idea of ​​its distinctions.  Then
we will know about the details of this company.
Meaning what does the company do?
What could be the future of companies of which sector?
Then we will know its financial fundamentals.
Meaning, whether the company is in profit or loss
and whether it is more
expensive or cheaper than its competitors etc.  Then
we will know about the details of this IPO and
finally we will know whether we should apply for this IPO or
not.  Tax
listing is according to this or long term.
So we will clear all the things
in this video.
Before starting the video, friends, the links of Telegram,
Instagram, WhatsApp, Facebook
are inside the description.  Join and keep it.
And look friends, I will clear all the things for
you in this video.  But
you have to take the decision by taking your own risk and doing your own analysis.  There
is no buy or sell recommendation.  Okay, right?  You should keep this thing
in mind and whatever
discussion happens about GMP etc. is just an
idea and is being known for reference.
Rest, you should not rely on it nor should
you take any decision based on it.  Everything
is clear.  So the first thing is the
GMP grey market premium which is
saying around 10%.
Initially it was around 12%.  Right now
its latest demand is coming around 10%.
GMP as I told you is
not a fixed parameter.  It keeps going up and down.   There is
no need to trust at all.  The stock is trading at ₹220 as of
today.  Right now the
demand is good.  Okay, right?  Not bad.
Then let's talk about its anchor risk.  The anchor
list is out.  It has come out quite well.
Its total issue size is ₹10.63 crore and
₹322 crore has been raised by anchor investors.  We
can assume it to be around 30%.
So if we talk about
mutual funds, this company is also a mutual
fund company.  Okay, right?  So
if we talk about mutual funds, then some names like HDFC, AMC, SBI Mutual
Fund, Withk, Helioss, Kotak, Axis, Aitya
Bla, DSP, Quant, apart from that HSBC,
Invesco, Edelb, PGIM
are included.  Along with that, if we
talk about global investors, then Capital
Group, Monetary Authority of Singapore,
CLS Global, Fidelity, JP Morgan,
Government Pension Fund, BlackRock,
Goldmanx, Amand, Abu Dhabi, Pidenial which is
also a partner of this company, Prudential.
Many such big names like Sosh General
are included in the FI list.  Apart from that,
insurance companies are also included.
Meaning, if you look at the overall anchor list, it is quite
good.  There is a good INF
name within FIIs.  There are good enough names within mutual funds also.
So its anchor list can
easily be given a rating of 8.5.  A very
good anchor list has come.  If seen in GMP, then
half a point is given and in anchor list,
one full point is given.  Then let's talk
about the details of this company, that is, what
work does this company do.  So the company was
incorporated in 1993.   It has been almost
32 years
in my own sector.  This company is an asset management
company.  You know almost everything in simple language.
AMC is also called mutual fund company.
Okay, right?  Asset means money, it
manages people's money.
What happens inside a mutual fund is that we
invest money.  They manage this.
Different schemes, funds etc. are launched.
Mid cap funds, small cap funds.  So they
manage them.  And their biggest work
is mutual funds.  Okay, right?  And the second
work is portfolio management service.
Portfolios are also managed by people.
They have different schemes within that too.
So under that it means it manages the portfolio of people.  Apart from that,
it has
alternative investment funds.  This is what AIF is
called.  Now if we look at it, most of
its revenue comes from mutual funds.
And if we look at India, most of the
revenue, 98%, comes from India.  The rest can
assume something like 2% from outside.
Overall, if we look at AMC and
mutual funds, then this is the second largest mutual fund company in
India in terms of AM assets under management.  If
you ask which is the second largest, then which is the first, then the
first is SBI
AMC, the top one, I mean I have also seen that SBI
funds perform very well,
so it is at the top number one, at second number is
ICIC AMC, then at third number is HDFC AMC,
at fourth is Nipon, at fifth is Kotak,
at sixth is Aditya Birla, in this way AE
means who has how much asset, so SBI
manages assets worth more than Rs 11 lakh crore and ICICI
manages assets worth more than Rs 10 lakh crore.  Then they keep
coming down like this.  So, it's a big
advantage that it's the second largest.  It
is a top leading company in its sector.  This is a
very good thing.  And another good thing is
that there are largest number of schemes.
Meaning, if we look at the 143 schemes it has,
it has almost the highest number of mutual fund schemes in the industry.  It is
spread across three states and four union territories.  It has a total of 272
offices.  And if we look at the mutual fund business, then
it has a market share of approximately 13.3% of all the mutual funds being sold in India.  So that's a
pretty good thing.  The company
looks quite good.  Now let us
also know its financial fundamentals.  So the financials are
given from 2023 to 2025 and are given till September
of FR 26.  But if we
look at the whole year now, we will see only till 2025.
So if you look inside the assets, there is growth year after
year.  Very good growth.  The
same year-on-year growth is being seen in revenue as well.
Almost you can say that there is more than 1.5 times
growth in revenue.
Tremendous growth is also being seen in profits.  If we
calculate the profit margin, it is
above 50% every year.
53% in 2023, 54% in 2024, 53% in 2025, that
means half a percent up or down is a different thing.
Rest, having 50% margin is also a big thing,
almost all the mutual fund companies have
margins like this, around 50% 45%, which is
very good.  So you can imagine
how much commission the mutual fund companies
take from us.  There is a difference if we invest a particular amount ourselves
or through a mutual fund company.
She does take her fees.  There is a
small fee but it is a huge earning for them.  If a
huge amount of
money is invested then their percentage is made and
they earn money.  The rest is growth in net worth.
Growth was seen within the reserves.
It has reserves of ₹3900 crore and no debt.  It
is a debt free company.  So
you can call it an ideal company.  The company is good, the
financials are also good.  Such ideal companies are
rarely seen.  Generally,
I have seen the same thing in mutual fund companies.
So this is also a good company.
ROE and Return on Net Worth 82.8% is
excellent.  The minimum criteria is that
if the ROE, ROC etc. is
15% then it is good.  Its 82.8
is very good.  Now if we look at its valuations,
its PE is 40.4 and other
listed peers are
all smaller companies in terms of revenue and AUM.  There
is only one big company, SBI,
AMC, it is not listed.  Rest
is HDFC listed.  Nipon, UTI and Aitya Birla are
all listed.  These are all smaller companies than this.
So their PE ranges from 19.8 to 45.2
and his is 40.4.  So if we look at it, we
cannot say that the valuations are very expensive.
Yes, it can be said that it is not cheap either.
Okay, right?  It would have been better if it was cheaper but it is
not too expensive either.
If we look at the most expensive stock today,
HDFC AMC seems to be a bit expensive.  PE wise
valuations are correct.  Meaning it
is not very expensive.  It is not cheap either.  It is
not very expensive either.  Then if we talk about the details of this IPO, then
this IPO will remain open between 12th to 16th December.  The
face value is coming to ₹1.  The price
band has been kept between ₹261 to ₹2165.
This is a lot of six shares.  Meaning, it
seems a little inside that it would have been
better if it was made lighter and cheaper.
If this price band was between Rs 1800 and Rs 1500, it would have been
better.  I have
n't seen it yet, it is not that expensive.
Okay, right?  It doesn't look that expensive either.  It is
not very cheap either.
You should keep this thing in mind.  Meaning
they did not keep much margin.  Normal
margins have been maintained.  The issue size is around ₹10,6003
crore.  It is a complete OFS
because looking at the company, there is
no need for any money and this is a
partnership between both ICICI and PDL.
Earlier, ICICI had 51% and
Potential had 49%.  What happened after that?
What did they do before bringing the IPO that
after the IPO,
ICICI Bank will have 53% stake and 47% potential, so
they are selling around 10% of that
potential, so later it will be left with 37% potential.
So if we look at the promoter's holding overall,
initially it is 100% and later it will be around 90%.
So if it is 90% then it is
necessary to make the promoter's
holding minimum 75%.  According to this, it seems that
later they will bring FPO or will sell it, which
means there will be listing.  Well, once he reaches this position, he will
take more advantage of it.
So the promoters used their brains.
Its remaining market cap will be above Rs 1 lakh crore.
Meaning you can say that it will be categorized as a large cap
company.  So it
is a very big company.  So this growth that you are
thinking that the money will double instantly is
not possible.  It will take some time.  But
yes, this seems to be a good company.
According to this, if a large cap company has such a
huge market cap, then its growth can only be
slow.  A small cap
company is one whose market cap is small,
so it does not take time to grow.
So keep this thing in mind while
moving forward.  I am not saying that you should
not apply for this, there will be double or not.
I am not saying that.
I am just explaining to you Babu
with an example that if the market cap is so big then it will
work accordingly.  The listing date for the remaining retail portion of 35% is
December 19.  So these are the
complete IPO details.  Now the main
question is whether to apply for this IPO
?  Don't do it.  If you do it then do it according to the listing
gains in the long term.
Look, I had told you that
I will clear everything for you.  You have to
take the decision by applying your risk and your analysis.  There
is no buy or sell recommendation.  Whatever
decision you take will be your own.  And what has been
discussed about GMP etc. is
just an estimate.  One should not rely on it
nor take decisions based on it.  And you should
not take any decision based on the information I have given you.  I have shared this information only
for your educational purpose.  So
keeping this in mind, you will take any
decision.  Ok?  Rest of the links of Telegram,
Instagram, WhatsApp, Facebook
are inside the description.  Please join.
So first of all, those who
want to apply as per the listing age and we
see four parameters normally.  So the first
thing is GMP.  GMP is just an estimate
but let's see.  So right now GMP
is showing around 10%.  So our minimum
criteria for GMP is that if it is 20% then it is fine.
And right now it is 10% so let's give half a point within it.
Then the anchor list.  The anchor has
come very well.  A full point is
awarded for the anchors.  Valuations Valuations
are fine.  So half a point is found in valuations.  I have
received a good subscription.  As
of today, we have
received good subscription on the very first day.  Meaning the
issue size is so big.  According to that, if it is a good
subscription then you can
easily give half a point in the subscription.  So if we
count the total, 28 points are being scored out of 4.
Meaning, if we look at it, these parameters are being created from neutral to
risk free.
Rest I am not saying that you should
apply for it or not.
I am telling you about these paratroopers who are being formed.
Then if we talk in the long term, we can
look at the positive and negative.   The
positive thing is that if we look at a company, it
appears to be a perfect ideal company.
Meaning the company's business is good.  It
is the top leading second largest company in the
mutual fund business.  So
what more could you ask for?  At the same time, the
financials are very good.  Meaning there
is growth in revenue.  There is growth within profit.
Profit margins are good.  Above 50%.
Meaning, what kind of business is there that has a
profit margin of 50%.  So this
is great.  The second thing is debt free company.
Reserves are also in its hands.  Meaning a cash
rich company can be called an ideal company.
ROE ROC is above 80%.  This means such a
good thing.  Rest of the promoter
holdings are good.  We may sell it later
but it is good right now.  Very good
promoter holding.  So it can be called a perfect
ideal company.  What
are negatives?  It is important to remove the negatives also.   The
negatives are that if the valuations are made a little
cheaper, it would have been better.
Rest of the prices are still not very expensive
but the valuations are not very cheap.
Okay, right?  The thing is that if you
get something cheap in the market then it
tastes good or if you get it at very high rates then it tastes
good.  I don't like anything that is slightly expensive.
Apart from this, it is not that this will cause
much problem in these valuations
because all other factors
seem to be stronger.  Overall conclusion
wise, this factor is quite strong.  The
last Canara came from HSBC whose
GMP etc. was not working but
it had made a good performance but it was a small
company.  Okay, right?  This is quite big.  So, do
not expect too much that you will suddenly get
bumper profits.  This is not necessary
because large cap is a big company, so it
takes some time.  Okay, right?  Overall,
I don't think there is much problem in this.
Meaning it does
not appear to be a risky company.  It seems to be a completely risk free company.
Apart from this, there is
no buy or sell recommendation from my side.  Whatever decision you make, make it after taking
your own risk and doing your own analysis.  Please do
let us know what you will do by commenting.  And after watching this video, have
all your doubts been cleared or not?  Please do let
me know by commenting whether each point has been cleared or not.  See you
guys in the next video.